A Guide to the W.E. Bibb Papers
University of Virginia Library
Buckner business correspondence mentions the following subjects: slaves belonging to the mother of E.B. Brock(1855 Dec 22); the lack of success in getting farmers to come to Virginia to work the farms for half shares (1870 Dec 15); the widow of John Terrell seeking a pension based on the service of her husband with Captain Bentley Brown's Company(1871 Dec 20); the estate of Buckner's mother (1873 Aug 21); references to prejudice, " Clayton will not rent again if any of the negroes do" (1873 Sep 10); malpractice accusations of C.T. Brown and squabbles over the teaching payments (1874 Sep 25, Oct 1, 3, & 5); an inquiry about a pyrite mine near Buckner(1884 Apr 7); a marriage certificate needed for A.J. Yarbough and W.S. Kirk, married 1881 Oct 11, due to death of husband in an accident (1885 Sep 12); Warner Hall disability certificate (1885 Sep 20); and the dependence of Susannah D. Mills on the hire of her slaves to pay family expenses [pre 1865].
The Buckner family personal correspondence is chiefly between Dr. Buckner and his wayward son, Horace Buckner(d. 1888), out West in St. Louis, Baton Rouge, and elsewhere, and includes: the birth of a son to Baldwin and Moldy (1854 Oct 11); the death of little Matt (1856 Nov 9); the visit of Yankees frightening Buckner's wife Moldy and the death of Moldy (1864 Apr 20); Horace Buckner with General Johnston in Georgia and his participation in the Battle of New Hope Church(1864 Jun 23); Horace Buckner from Mobile, Alabama, describes the replacing of all southern officials by a military government and Yankee sympathizers, African-Americans working on shares in agricultural jobs, the emigration to Brazil of a flourishing colony of Southerners, an offer to take charge of a mercantile business on a branch of the Amazon River, and a request to present a speech before the Philo Mathematician Society on July fourth (1867 Jun 8); a "testimonial" for chances in advancement out West (1869 Dec 11); a description of Nebraska and Minnesota(1870 Dec 24); a reference to astrology (1871 Apr 24); and industrial accident in Horace Buckner's dyeing and tailoring establishment (1871 Sep 26); a reference to "Mardi Gras" in Baton Rouge(1874 Feb 22); Horace Buckner's problem with gambling and drinking (1875 May 13); Horace Buckner has his hand bitten through in a fracas on Saturday (1876 Feb 9); his brother Robert Buckner about Horace Buckner([187?); a testimonial that Captain H. Buckner is not dissipated (1880 May 11); and the amputation of a woman's knee due to cancer (1882 Sep 14 & 27).
The papers of Reuben Lindsay Gordon(1855-1939), Commonwealth's Attorney for Louisa County for sixteen years, elected to the House of Delegates in 1914 where he served until 1928, and member of the Constitutional Convention in 1901-1902, consist of business and legal papers and correspondence. Gordon was born in Edgewoth, Albemarle County and educated privately by his father, William F. Gordon, and was married (1884) first to Alice Maud Winston(1860-1919) and subsequently to Nellie Blair Hunt. The business and legal papers include a reference to elections in Louisa County, including Daniel Gordon and R.L. Gordon, Jr.(1881 Sep 6); a mention by Maury Morris of fox hunting (1880 Sep 16); a suit involving an African-American male (1886 Jul 13); and the death of Gordon's mother (1887 Apr 9).
Correspondents include A.B. Grymes, William F. Gordon, Jr., Mary Jane Gordon(1852-1891), Alexander T. Gordon(1862-1943), his brother-in-law, J.O. Winston, sister, B.L. Gordon, and Cassius Carter. Subjects in the correspondence include opportunities for lawyers in Texas(1884 Aug 26); work as a locating engineer for a railroad in Texas(1887 Apr 3); and the poor postal service in Metz, Texas(1887 Aug 27).
The papers of John Goodwin May are chiefly concerned with his legal duties as a practicing lawyer in Louisa County, with separate folders for correspondence concerning the installation of an electric light plant for the town of Louisa(1903) and the inventory of stock of John F. Tolley & Bro.(1905). The legal cases folder contains a suit by Mary L. (Baker) Massie vs the Grand Lodge Knights of Pythias; the estates of W.J. Underwood and Jeff Porter; and the Mamie Thomas and J.B. Thomas Divorce Case. His personal and political correspondence includes: a disagreement with the Rev. L.J. Haley(1904 Sep 1; 1905 Aug 30); the death of May's father (1913 Mar 18); a controversy with R.L. Gordon(1913 Mar 25); correspondence with George S. Shackelford(1914 Jun 16); the Cumberland Sanitorium, Lebanon, Tennessee(1916 Jul 3); offer of services to the government during World War I (1917 Jun 30-Aug 27); warning not to use cocaine with another remedy (1917 Nov 8); and a description of her student life by his daughter Gladys May in Baltimore during World War I (1917 Nov 23, n.d.).
The business and legal papers of Robert F. Moss(d. 1883), sheriff of Louisa County, include: a letter from William Gilman to Moss regarding the next election to the Virginia House of Delegates where, "I trust Louisa will be redeemed and that instead of negroes and white Radicals I will meet a simon pure Virginian delegation from your good old county," (1875 Oct 25); notification of the escape of an inmate from the Central Lunatic Asylum near Richmond who was probably headed for Louisa(1881 Feb 16); and concerning the primary election, H.V. Winston asking for support in the upcoming election (1880 Jul 1).
John Q. Rhodes was the law partner of W.C. Bibb in the 1920's and his business and legal papers chiefly pertain to his legal work in Louisa County. In 1936, Rhodes became director of the Division of Motor Vehicles for Virginia. He served as a member of the House of Delegates from 1930-1934. His correspondence contains very little personal material and is chiefly concerned with the legal cases he represented. An unusual item in the business and legal papers is a prospectus of the Haile Gold Mines, Inc.(1937 Jul 15).
The personal and political folder contains a booklet of admission tickets for delegates to the 1924 Democratic National Convention in New York and the declaration of Rhodes for candidacy with supporting papers for the House of Delegates from Louisa County to Carl H. Nolting, Chairman of the Louisa County Democratic Committee(1933 May 9).
Among the papers related to Louisa County elections and politics are: the Louisa Camp Confederate Veterans Roll; election returns (n.d.); poll books; used primary election ballots for 1905; and voting lists (1895 & n.d.) with separate "white" and "colored" lists. There is also some political material in a folder labelled "Miscellaneous: Political & Miscellaneous Documents."
Businesses represented in this series include: Craig Kennels and Game Farm, Trevilians, Virginia, all concerning debt collection; a lawsuit involving the Jackson Telephone and Telegraph Company; The Old Dominion Phonograph Company, Roanoke, Virginia, containing an annual report (1890) and stock certificates belonging to W.E. Bibb; and the Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing, and Land Company. The directors of this company were R.P. Talley(President), W.H.F. Lee(Vice-President), W.R. Goodwin(General Manager), P.B. Porter(Secretary & Treasurer, replaced by A.G. Hill in June 1890), W.E. Bibb(Attorney), W.O. Smith, J.F. Bickers, and J.W. Flannagan. Most of the correspondence was handled by P.B. Porter and then A.G. Hill, and was concerned with a new C & O Railroad depot (1890 Apr 11 & 19), a petition to change the name of the town of Tolersville to Mineral City(1890 Apr 17), questions about the charter, the prospectus of the company, the purchase of stock shares, and advertisements concerning the property. Other types of papers include: bills & receipts, financial statements, pay rolls, printed material, and a time book (for bound volumes pertaining to the Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing, and Land Company see Boxes 40-42). For a recent discussion of the history of Mineral and the Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing, and Land Company see the Louisa County Historical Magazine, Spring 1990 Mineral Centennial Issue, Volume 21, No. 1, pages 15-27.
Series III: Boyd Smith Papers
The Boyd Smith mines were first opened about 1886 by Boyd Smith, who was also President of the Pyrites Mining & Chemical Company. The mines were never as successful as the nearby Arminius Mines and much of his business and legal papers deal with claims made against Boyd Smith and his company, law suits against Boyd Smith, and attempts to interest various mining companies in purchasing his mines in Louisa County. There is a fair amount of correspondence with W.E. Bibb who was his legal representative in Louisa and who was appointed Special Commissioner to sell the Pyrites Mining & Chemical Company in November of 1900. These files also contain Boyd Smith's personal business and legal papers such as late life insurance payments, bills, and other matters. Also present are inventories of the stores and tools at the pyrite mines listed for potential buyers of the property (1900 August & October; 1901 Apr) and examples of the Pyrites Chemical & Mining Company store script (see separate folder).
The folder of family and personal correspondence, 1897-1903, contains mainly letters from his son, D. Boyd Smith to his father, one from his wife [Bliss ?] (1902 May 14), and a photograph of [Bliss ?] and Mrs. Bibb(1901).
Series IV: William Worth Smith, Jr. Papers
This series consists chiefly of the legal cases handled by William Worth Smith, Jr.(1887-?), a Virginia State Senator from 1924-1934, arranged alphabetically by the name of the claimant. William Worth Smith Jr.'s papers are concerned predominantly with the collection of debts for his clients but they also contain separate folders of a slander case, cases of divorce, the purchase of "Ionia Farm, and law suits. William Worth Smith Jr.'s correspondence folder includes letters of a political nature from Claude Swanson, Charles C. Carlin, Howard W. Smith, and A. Willis Robertson. William Worth Smith Jr. was born in Fauquier County to William Worth Smith and Lucinda Lewis Smith and was educated at Randolph-Macon College and the University of Virginia, receiving his law degree in 1910. He was married to Lucy Winston Sims, daughter of Judge F.W. Sims, and became a dairy farmer in Louisa County. His only brother was Representative Howard Smith of the Eighth District.
Series V: Bound Volumes & Oversize Material
This series has three subseries based on the size of the items, a) boxed bound volumes, b) 2M bound volumes and c) oversize folders, and arranged alphabetically within subseries according to the name of the individual or business concerned with the item.
Container List
- SERIES I: W.E. BIBB & BIBB FAMILY PAPERS
  - Bibb, James E.: Correspondence with W.E. Bibb., 1890-1898; (2 folders). (Box Box 1.)
  - Bibb, John P.: Business & Legal Papers., 1903-1909; (2 folders). (Box Box 1.)
  - Bibb, John P.: Business & Legal Papers - Trustee for Rich & Cornevin, Louisa County., 1909-1910 (Box Box 1.)
  - Bibb, John P.: Correspondence., 1907-1909 (Box Box 1.)
  - Bibb, W.C.: Business & Legal Papers., 1906-1924 (Box Box 1.)
  - Bibb, W.C.: Independent Order of Odd Fellows Papers., 1904-1910, n.d. (Box Box 1.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Business Papers - Accounts & Receipts., 1874-1891 Jun; (2 folders). (Box Box 1.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Business Papers - Accounts & Receipts., 1891 Jul-1905, n.d.; (5 folders). (Box Box 2.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Business Correspondence., 1889-1891; (5 folders). (Box Box 2.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Business Correspondence., 1892-1894; (7 folders). (Box Box 3.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Business Correspondence., 1895-1897; (6 folders). (Box Box 4.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Business Correspondence., 1898-1908, n.d.; (7 folders). (Box Box 5.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with Arminius Chemical Company., 1891-1898 (Box Box 5.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with Arminius Chemical Company., 1899-1903; (2 folders). (Box Box 6.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with W.L. Bishop., 1890-1909 (Box Box 6.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with J.R. Crank., 1890-1903; (2 folders). (Box Box 6.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with Charles Goodloe., 1890-1901 (Box Box 6.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with Thomas J. Harmon., 1890-1892 (Box Box 6.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with Mrs. B.M. (Hasher) Loving., 1893-1903; (2 folders) (Box Box 6.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence re Mining Properties., 1890-1903; (3 folders) (Box Box 7.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with Ella R. Moss., 1882-1898; (2 folders) (Box Box 7.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with Nelms & Wise., 1899-1903 (Box Box 7.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with Samuel H. Parsons., 1890-1891 (Box Box 7.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with J.F. Reynolds., 1898-1901 (Box Box 7.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Correspondence with Helen Summers., 1893-1898 (Box Box 7.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Family Correspondence., 1890-1903, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 8.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Cases - Andrews (Samuel) Executors vs. John J. Trice, et al., 1860, 1872-1887, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 8.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Cases - A-J., 1879-1907 (Box Box 8.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Cases - Divorce., 1891-1909 (Box Box 8.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Cases - K-Y., 1877-1905; (3 folders) (Box Box 8.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Cases - Miscellaneous Notes., n.d. (Box Box 9.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Correspondence., 1882-1893 Jun; (8 folders) (Box Box 9.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Correspondence., 1893 Jul-1896 Mar; (8 folders) (Box Box 10.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Correspondence., 1896 Apr-1899 May; (8 folders) (Box Box 11.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Correspondence., 1899 Jun-1901; (10 folders). (Box Box 12.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Correspondence., 1902-1909, n.d. (Box Box 13.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Forms., n.d. (Box Box 13.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Legal Papers., 1874-1902 (Box Box 13.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Personal Correspondence., 1890-1904 (Box Box 14.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Political Correspondence., 1872-1904; (5 folders). (Box Box 14.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Political Correspondence - Daniel, John W.., 1891-1900 (Box Box 14.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Political Correspondence - Ellyson, J. Taylor (Chairman) and the Virginia State Democratic Committee., 1894-1901 (Box Box 14.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Political Correspondence - Little, William A.., 1890-1896 (Box Box 14.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Political Correspondence - Martin, Thomas S.., 1892-1903 (Box Box 14.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Political Correspondence - Meredith, E.E.., 1893-1897 (Box Box 14.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Political Correspondence - O'Ferrall, Charles T.., 1892-1893 (Box Box 14.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Political Correspondence - Powell, R.R.., 1893-1897 (Box Box 14.)
  - Bibb, W.E.: Political Correspondence - Rixey, John F.., 1896-1904 (Box Box 14.)
- SERIES II: MISCELLANEOUS LOUISA COUNTY FAMILIES
  - Boxley, John: Estate of., 1912-1928; (3 folders). (Box Box 15.)
  - Boxley, John: Estate of - Accounts of John J. Boxley, Jr. and Virginia Boxley., 1915-1917 (Box Box 15.)
  - Buck, H.C., Jr.: Business & Legal Papers., 1906-1909 (Box Box 15.)
  - Buckner Family: Accounts & Receipts., 1836-1869; ((4 folders). (Box Box 15.)
  - Buckner Family: Accounts & Receipts., 1870-1886; (5 folders). (Box Box 16.)
  - Buckner Family: Business Correspondence., 1848-1887; (2 folders). (Box Box 16.)
  - Buckner Family: Legal Papers., 1860-1929 (Box Box 16.)
  - Buckner Family: Personal Correspondence., 1854-1887 (Box Box 16.)
  - Chiles, John: Estate of, including a list of slaves., 1846 Jan 3 (Box Box 17.)
  - Craig Kennels and Game Farm, Trevilians, Virginia., 1936-1941 (Box Box 17.)
  - Fletcher, Mary: Estate of, Administrated by Dr. Baldwin M. Buckner., 1852-1880 (Box Box 17.)
  - Gordon, R.L.: Business & Legal Papers., 1868-1886; (8 folders). (Box Box 17.)
  - Gordon, R.L.: Business & Legal Papers., 1887-1889, 1916-1917, n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 18.)
  - Gordon, R.L.: Correspondence., 1877-1887, n.d. (Box Box 18.)
  - Jackson Telephone and Telegraph Company., 1906-1909 (Box Box 18.)
  - Johnson, George H.: Business & Legal Papers., 1900-1919 (Box Box 18.)
  - Louisa Camp Confederate Veterans Roll (copied for W.E. Bibb by W.T. Meade, Adj.)., n.d. (Box Box 18.)
  - Louisa County: Election Returns., n.d. (Box Box 18.)
  - Louisa County: Poll Books., 1907-1908; (2 folders). (Box Box 19.)
  - Louisa County Primary Election Ballots., 1905 (Box Box 19.)
  - Louisa County: Voting Lists., 1895, n.d. (Box Box 19.)
  - May, John G.: Business & Legal Correspondence., 1906-1919 (Box Box 19.)
  - May, John G.: Business & Legal Papers., 1896-1917 (Box Box 19.)
  - May, John G.: Correspondence re the Installation of an Electric Plant., 1903 (Box Box 19.)
  - May, John G.: Inventory of Stock of John F. Tolley & Bro., taken July 5, 1905. (Box Box 19.)
  - May, John G.: Legal Cases., 1904-1905, 1914-1916 (Box Box 19.)
  - May, John G.: Personal & Political Correspondence., 1904-1917 (Box Box 19.)
  - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing and Land Company., 1889-1890; (9 folders). (Box Box 20.)
  - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing and Land Company., 1891-1892; (8 folders). (Box Box 21.)
  - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing and Land Company., 1893-1905, n.d.; (2 folders). (Box Box 22.)
  - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing and Land Company - Bills & Receipts., 1890-1891; (5 folders). (Box Box 22.)
  - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing and Land Company - Financial Statements., 1890-1892 (Box Box 22.)
  - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing and Land Company - Pay Rolls., 1890-1891 (Box Box 23.)
  - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing and Land Company - Printed Material., 1890-1898 (Box Box 23.)
  - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing and Land Company - Time Book., 1890 (Box Box 23.)
  - Miscellaneous: Business & Legal Papers., 1830-1940, n.d.; (4 folders). (Box Box 23.)
  - Miscellaneous: Correspondence., 188[6?]-1918 (Box Box 23.)
  - Miscellaneous: Political & Miscellaneous Documents., 1891-1931, n.d. (Box Box 23.)
  - Miscellaneous: Stock Certificates., 1891-1892, n.d. (Box Box 23.)
  - Mosby, Joseph R.: Estate of, Administered by James E. Bibb., ca. 1881-1883 (Box Box 23.)
  - Moss, Robert F.: Business & Legal Papers., 1870-1879 (Box Box 23.)
  - Moss, Robert F.: Business & Legal Papers., 1880-1883 (Box Box 24.)
  - The Old Dominion Phonograph Company., 1890-1893 (Box Box 24.)
  - Rhodes, J.Q.: Business & Legal Papers., 1923-1940, n.d.; (5 folders). (Box Box 24.)
  - Rhodes, J.Q.: Personal & Political Papers., 1920-1933, n.d. (Box Box 24.)
  - Sharp, Ellis: Correspondence., 1911-1912 (Box Box 24.)
  - Thomasson, J.G.: Guardianship of Brothers & Sisters., 1901-1905 (Box Box 24.)
- SERIES III: BOYD SMITH PAPERS
  - Smith, Boyd M.: Business & Legal Papers., 1884-1897 (Box Box 24.)
  - Smith, Boyd M.: Business & Legal Papers., 1898-1904, n.d.; (10 folders). (Box Box 25.)
  - Smith, Boyd M.: Business & Legal Papers - Contract., 1902 (Box Box 26.)
  - Smith, Boyd M.: Business & Legal Papers - Miscellaneous Accounts., ca. 1901-1902 (Box Box 26.)
  - Smith, Boyd M.: Family & Personal Correspondence., 1897-1903 (Box Box 26.)
  - Smith, Boyd M.: Pyrites Chemical & Mining Company., 1902, n.d. (Box Box 26.)
  - Smith, Boyd M.: The Pyrites Chemical & Mining Company, Mineral City, Virginia vs The National Fertilizer Company, Nashville, Tennessee., 1898-1901 (Box Box 26.)
- SERIES IV: WILLIAM WORTH SMITH, JR. PAPERS
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Correspondence., 1913-1915, 1923-1930 (Box Box 26.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - A-Be., 1913-1922; (4 folders). (Box Box 26.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Bi-Ch., 1897-1922; (5 folders). (Box Box 27.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Chattanooga Medicine Company., 1914-1921 (Box Box 27.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Ci-Cl., 1912-1920 (Box Box 27.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Coles, Ed & Susan vs Greenbrier Putty (Slander Case)., 1915 (Box Box 27.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Commonwealth of Virginia., 1913-1915 (Box Box 27.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Co-Cu., 1914-1921 (Box Box 27.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Da-Di., 1913-1919 (Box Box 28.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Divorce., 1913-1916 (Box Box 28.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Dm-Gw., 1912-1922; (5 folders). (Box Box 28.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - H-I., 1912-1922; (6 folders). (Box Box 29.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - "Ionia Farm," Purchase of., 1914-1915 (Box Box 29.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - J-K., 1879-1922; (4 folders). (Box Box 29.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Louisa Hardware Company claims., 1913-1919 (Box Box 30.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - La-O., 1910-1921; (8 folders). (Box Box 30.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Orange County News claims., 1920-1921 (Box Box 30.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Oxweld Acetylene Company vs W.T. Davis and Fred Dixon., 1917-1919 (Box Box 31.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Pa-Pi., 1913-1921; (2 folders). (Box Box 31.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Pleasants, A.G. claims., 1912-1915 (Box Box 31.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Po-Q., 1907-1920; (3 folders). (Box Box 31.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - R-S., 1904-1921; (8 folders). (Box Box 32.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - T-W., 1910-1921; (9 folders). (Box Box 33.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Allan C. Wood vs C.P. Vaughan., 1917 (Box Box 33.)
  - Smith, William Worth, Jr.: Legal Cases - Yancey, L.F.., 1911-1915 (Box Box 33.)
- SERIES V: BOUND VOLUMES & OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - SUBSERIES A: BOXED BOUND VOLUMES
    - Bibb, John Pendleton: Account Book, with index, as Trustee of Rich & Cornevin, Louisa County, Virginia., 1909 (Box Box 34.)
    - Bibb, John Pendleton: Ledger, with index, as Trustee of Rich & Cornevin, Louisa County, Virginia., 1908-1910 (Box Box 34.)
    - Bibb, W.E.: Bank Books (see Box 44) (Box Box 34.)
    - Bibb, W.E.: Index Rerum kept by W.E. Bibb concerning legal topics. (Box Box 34.)
    - [Bibb, W.E.]: Legal Diaries, with notes concerning law cases., 1872-1877, [1884]; (2 volumes). (Box Box 34.)
    - Bibb, W.E.: Letterbooks, with indexes., 1877-1894; (3 volumes). (Box Box 35.)
    - Bibb, W.E.: Letterbooks, with indexes., 1894-1897; (3 volumes). (Box Box 36.)
    - Bibb, W.E.: Letterbook, with index., 1897-1900 (Box Box 37.)
    - Buckner, Dr. B.M.: Ledger., 1853-1865 (Box Box 37.)
    - Buckner, Dr. B.M.: Index to Ledger., 1853-1865 (Box Box 37.)
    - Buckner, Dr. B.M.: Estate Ledger., 1861-1882 (Box Box 37.)
    - Buckner, Dr. B.M.: Estate Ledger Index., 1861-1882 (Box Box 37.)
    - Cameron, George V.: Daybook., [ca. 1908?] (Box Box 37.)
    - The Central Virginian Newspaper: Minutes of the Board of Directors., 1915 & 1919 (Box Box 37.)
    - Flannagan and Talley: Journal., 1881-1884 (Box Box 38.)
    - Louisa Guano Company: Ledgers., 1896-1902; (2 Volumes). (Box Box 38.)
    - Louisa Bargain House Ledgers, with indexes, Charles E. Hughes, Proprietor., 1902-1910; (4 volumes). (Box Box 39.)
    - Louisa Literary Club: Minute Book and Constitution of., 1885-1887 (Box Box 40.)
    - Louisa, Town of: Ledger., 1901-1917 (Box Box 40.)
    - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing & Land Company: Agents Commission Book., ca. 1890-1892 (Box Box 40.)
    - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing & Land Company: Board of Directors Minutes., 1890-1893 (Box Box 40.)
    - Mineral City, Mining, Manufacturing & Land Company: Journal., 1890-1892 (Box Box 40.)
    - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing & Land Company: Letterbooks with indexes, A.G. Hill., 1890-1892; (2 volumes). (Box Box 41.)
    - Mineral City Mining, Manufacturing & Land Company: Letterbook, W.R. Goodwin, etc.., 1890-1892 (Box Box 41.)